// questions for chris's quiz
const chrisQuestions = [
    {
        question: "How did Chris get the scar on his left leg?",
        choices: ["Falling down the stairs", "During a basketball game", "Getting stuck on a fence", "Playing soccer in Mexico"],
        answer: "Playing soccer in Mexico"
    },

    {
        question: "What language would Chris like to learn?",
        choices: ["English", "Chinese", "Vietnamese", "Italian"],
        answer: "Vietnamese"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Chris's favorite season?",
        choices: ["Fall", "Spring", "Winter", "Summer"],
        answer: "Winter"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Chris's favorite music to listen to?",
        choices: ["90's", "70's", "80's", "2000's"],
        answer: "80's"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Chris's favorite ice cream flavor?",
        choices: ["Chocolate", "Mint Chocolate", "Vanilla", "Strawberry"],
        answer: "Mint Chocolate",
    },

    {
        question: "What is Chris's favorite car?",
        choices: ["Mustang", "Toyota", "Honda", "Porsche"],
        answer: "Toyota"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Chris's favorite invention?",
        choices: ["Loki Scepter", "Gauntlet", "Arc Reactor", "The whole Avengers set"],
        answer: "The whole avengers set"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Chris's favorite jacket?",
        choices: ["Winter coat", "Leather jacket", "Fur Coat", "Robe"],
        answer: "Winter coat"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Chris's favorite shoes?",
        choices: ["Running Shoes", "Basketball Shoes", "Pantuflas", "PF Flyers"],
        answer: "Basketball Shoes"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Chris's favorite flower?",
        choices: ["Tulips", "Daisies", "Roses", "Sunflowers"],
        answer: "Sunflowers"
    }
];

// questions for nataly's quiz
const natalyQuestions = [
    {
        question: "Why does Nataly look up to her dad?",
        choices: ["Patience and Love", "Knowledgeable, Reliable, and Logical", "Understanding and Caring", "Caring and Involved"],
        answer: "Knowledgeable, Reliable, and Logical"
    },

    {
        question: "If not a cosmetoligist, what would Nataly be?",
        choices: ["Accountant", "Fashion Designer", "Writer", "Therapist"],
        answer: "Writer"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Nataly's aesthetic?",
        choices: ["Preppy", "Grundge", "Granola Girl", "Emo"],
        answer: "Preppy"
    },

    {
        question: "When did Nataly start dying her hair?",
        choices: ["14", "13", "15", "16"],
        answer: "14"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Nataly's dream proposal?",
        choices: ["Campfire Proposal", "Disneyland in the Summer", "Disneyland in the Winter", "Sunset Proposal"],
        answer: "Disneyland in the Winter",
    },

    {
        question: "What is Nataly's favorite Star Wars character?",
        choices: ["Ahsoka Tano", "Padme", "Anakin", "Obi-Wan"],
        answer: "Ahsoka Tano"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Nataly's biggest fear in life?",
        choices: ["Dying alone", "Falling off a rollercoaster", "Everyone hating her", "Falling into a ditch"],
        answer: "Everyone hating her"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Nataly's go to karaoke song?",
        choices: ["Tierra Ajena", "Getaway Car", "White Horse", "Noviembre Sin Ti"],
        answer: "Tierra Ajena"
    },

    {
        question: "How often does Nataly wash her hair?",
        choices: ["Three times a week", "Two times week", "Everyday", "Every other day"],
        answer: "Three times a week"
    },

    {
        question: "What is one part of Nataly's body that is always cold?",
        choices: ["Feet", "Hands", "Neck", "Nose"],
        answer: "Handss"
    }
];

// questions for Mikey's quiz
const mikeyQuestions = [
    {
        question: "What is Mikey's favorite animal?",
        choices: ["Axolotl", "Chameleon", "Peacock", "Manta Ray"],
        answer: "Manta Ray"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Mikey's favorite food?",
        choices: ["Korean BBQ", "Chicken Wings", "PIZZA", "Lasagna"],
        answer: "Chicken Wings"
    },

    {
        question: "What was Mikey's first anime?",
        choices: ["Fairy Tail", "My Hero Academia", "Fruits Basket", "Haikyuu!!"],
        answer: "Fruits Basket"
    },

    {
        question: "Who's Mikey's favorite person?",
        choices: ["Valeria", "Chris", "Elias", "Estephania"],
        answer: "Elias"
    },

    {
        question: "What is Mikey's Favorite droid from Starwars",
        choices: ["BB-8", "R2-D2", "3-CPO", "D-O"],
        answer: "BB-8",
    },

    {
        question: "Who is Mikey's favorite disney princess?",
        choices: ["Mulan", "Rapunzel", "Belle", "Ariel"],
        answer: "Mulan"
    },

    {
        question: "How many animes have I watched?",
        choices: ["46", "193", "87", "59"],
        answer: "59"
    },

    {
        question: "How did I get the scar on my chin?",
        choices: ["Quique hit him", "Cut while cooking", "Fell on the stairs", "Baseball accident"],
        answer: "Fell on the stairs"
    },

    {
        question: "What are Mikey's favorite type of jeans?",
        choices: ["Black Denim", "Navy Denim", "Light Wash Denim", "Blue Denim"],
        answer: "Light wash Denim"
    },

    {
        question: "who is Mikey's favorite Hero?",
        choices: ["Spider Man", "The Flash", "Green Lantern", "Blue Beatle"],
        answer: "Blue Beatle"
    }
];

// questions for melissa's quiz
const melissaQuestions = [
    {
        question: "What is Melissa studying?", 
        choices: ["App Development", "Fullstack Web Development", "Back-end Web Development", "Front-End Web Development" ], 
        answer: "Fullstack Web Development"
    }, 
    {
        question: "What is Melissa's favorite childhood video game?", 
        choices: ["Dance Dance Revolution", "Just Dance", "Minecraft", "Tomb Raider"], 
        answer: "Tomb Raider"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Melissa's favorite makeup product?", 
        choices: ["Concealer", "Eyeliner", "Eyeshadow", "Eyebrow Gel"], 
        answer: "Eyeliner"
    }, 
    {
        question: "What was Melissa's childhood dream job?", 
        choices: ["Doctor", "Astronaut", "Teacher", "Vet"], 
        answer: "Teacher"
    }, 
    {
        question: "In what grade did Melissa get her glasses?", 
        choices: ["4th", "5th", "6th", "3rd"], 
        answer: "6th"
    }, 
    {
        question: "What is Melissa's favorite kind of chocolate?", 
        choices: ["Dark Chocolate", "Milk Chocolate", "White Chocolate", "Minty Chocolate" ], 
        answer: "Dark Chocolate"
    }, 
    {
        question: "Who is Melissa's favorite Star Wars droid?", 
        choices: ["BB-8", "R2D2", "C3PO", "D-O"], 
        answer: "BB-8"
    }, 
    {
        question: "What was one of Melissa's biggest insecurity growing up (ages 8-12)?", 
        choices: ["Curly hair", "Height", "Weight", "Lips"], 
        answer: "Curly hair"
    }, 
    {
        question: "Who was Melissa's favorite One Direction band member?", 
        choices: ["Harry", "Louis", "Niall", "Zayn"], 
        answer: "Zayn"
    }, 
    {
        question: "What grade did Melissa start homeschool?", 
        choices: ["5th", "6th", "7th", "4th"],
        answer: "7th" 
    }
];

// questions for Marlyn's quiz
const marlynQuestions = [
    {
        question: "If Marlyn could move, what state would she move to?", 
        choices: ["Wahington", "New York", "Arizona", "Texas" ], 
        answer: "Washington"
    }, 
    {
        question: "What is one language Marlyn would like to learn?", 
        choices: ["Chinese", "French", "Italian", "Sign Language"], 
        answer: "Sign Language"
    },
    {
        question: "Who is Marlyn's favorite Disney princess?", 
        choices: ["Belle", "Jasmine", "Rapunzel", "Cinderella"], 
        answer: "Jasmine"
    }, 
    {
        question: "Does Marlyn sleep with socks off or on?", 
        choices: ["On", "Off", "Doesn't matter"], 
        answer: "Off"
    }, 
    {
        question: "How many kids does Marlyn want?", 
        choices: ["5", "3 max", "3 min", "2"], 
        answer: "3 max"
    }, 
    {
        question: "When did Marlyn start doing her nails?", 
        choices: ["Junior Year", "Sophomore Year", "Freshman Year", "Junior High" ], 
        answer: "Sophomore Year"
    }, 
    {
        question: "If Marlyn could play one instrument, what would it be?", 
        choices: ["Violin", "Piano", "Guitar", "Trumpet"], 
        answer: "Piano"
    }, 
    {
        question: "What is something Marlyn would like to learn?", 
        choices: ["Skateboard", "Draw realistically", "Cook", "Surf"], 
        answer: "Skateboard"
    }, 
    {
        question: "What kind of tacos does Marlyn get?", 
        choices: ["Asada", "Buche", "Suadero", "Lengua"], 
        answer: "Asada"
    }, 
    {
        question: "What is Marlyn's favorite fast food place?", 
        choices: ["In n Out", "Wendy's", "Jack in the Box", "Chick fil A"],
        answer: "Wendy's" 
    }
];

const startBtn = document.getElementById("start");
const rules = document.getElementById("rules");
const titleWarning = document.getElementById("warning");

// timer variables
const seconds = document.createElement("p");
seconds.className = "timer";
let count = 120;

// score variable
let score = 0;

const currentScore = document.createElement("p");
currentScore.className = "timer";

// display question

let questionDisplay = document.createElement("p");
questionDisplay.className = "question-text col-12";
let currentQuestion = 0;

// show final score
const scoreDiv = document.getElementById("scoreContainer");

// play again ??
const playAgainBtn = document.createElement("button");
playAgainBtn.className = "btn btn-lg btn-outline-danger";
playAgainBtn.textContent = "Play Again";





function chooseQuiz() {
console.log("hey this is still working");
startBtn.className = "display-none";
rules.innerHTML = "";

const chooseWho = document.createElement("p");
chooseWho.textContent = "Who would you like to be quizzed on?"
chooseWho.className = "header-text";

const chrisBtn = document.createElement("button");
const natalyBtn = document.createElement("button");
const mikeyBtn = document.createElement("button");
const melissaBtn = document.createElement("button");
const marlynBtn = document.createElement("button");

chrisBtn.textContent = "Chris";
natalyBtn.textContent = "Nataly";
mikeyBtn.textContent = "Mikey";
melissaBtn.textContent = "Melissa";
marlynBtn.textContent = "Marlyn";

chrisBtn.className = "btn btn-lg btn-outline-success m-4 choose-who-text";
natalyBtn.className = "btn btn-lg btn-outline-info m-4 choose-who-text";
mikeyBtn.className = "btn btn-lg btn-outline-primary m-4 choose-who-text";
melissaBtn.className = "btn btn-lg btn-outline-secondary m-4 choose-who-text";
marlynBtn.className = "btn btn-lg btn-outline-warning m-4 choose-who-text";

rules.append(chooseWho, chrisBtn, natalyBtn, mikeyBtn, melissaBtn, marlynBtn);

chrisBtn.addEventListener("click", function () {
    let timer = setInterval(function () {
        count--;
        seconds.textContent = "Time left: " + count;
        titleWarning.appendChild(seconds);

        currentScore.textContent = `Your score : ${score}`;
        titleWarning.appendChild(currentScore);
        if (count < 1) {
            endQuiz();
            clearInterval(timer);
            console.log("the game has ended");
        }
    }, 1000);
    chrisQuiz();
});

natalyBtn.addEventListener("click", function () {
    let timer = setInterval(function () {
        count--;
        seconds.textContent = "Time left: " + count;
        titleWarning.appendChild(seconds);

        currentScore.textContent = `Your score : ${score}`;
        titleWarning.appendChild(currentScore);
        if (count < 1) {
            endQuiz();
            clearInterval(timer);
            console.log("the game has ended");
        }
    }, 1000);
    natalyQuiz();
});

mikeyBtn.addEventListener("click", function () {
    let timer = setInterval(function () {
        count--;
        seconds.textContent = "Time left: " + count;
        titleWarning.appendChild(seconds);

        currentScore.textContent = `Your score : ${score}`;
        titleWarning.appendChild(currentScore);
        if (count < 1) {
            endQuiz();
            clearInterval(timer);
            console.log("the game has ended");
        }
    }, 1000);
    mikeyQuiz();
});

melissaBtn.addEventListener("click", function () {
    console.log("hey this is melissa");
    let timer = setInterval(function () {
        count--;
        seconds.textContent = "Time left: " + count;
        titleWarning.appendChild(seconds);

        currentScore.textContent = `Your score : ${score}`;
        titleWarning.appendChild(currentScore);
        if (count < 1) {
            endQuiz();
            clearInterval(timer);
            console.log("the game has ended");
        }
    }, 1000);
    melissaQuiz();
}); 

marlynBtn.addEventListener("click", function () {
    let timer = setInterval(function () {
        count--;
        seconds.textContent = "Time left: " + count;
        titleWarning.appendChild(seconds);

        currentScore.textContent = `Your score : ${score}`;
        titleWarning.appendChild(currentScore);
        if (count < 1) {
            endQuiz();
            clearInterval(timer);
            console.log("the game has ended");
        }
    }, 1000);
    marlynQuiz();
});
};

// chris quiz
chrisQuiz = function () {
rules.innerHTML = '';

let question = chrisQuestions[currentQuestion];

rules.appendChild(questionDisplay);

for (i = 0; i < question.choices.length; i++) {
    questionDisplay.textContent = question.question;

    let answersBtn = document.createElement("button");
    answersBtn.className = "choices-class btn btn-lg btn-outline-dark m-2 col-4";
    answersBtn.textContent = question.choices[i];
    rules.append(answersBtn);
    answersBtn.addEventListener("click", chrisCheckAnswer);
};
}

function chrisCheckAnswer(event) {
let chosenAnswer = event.target.textContent;
console.log({ chosenAnswer });

if (chosenAnswer === chrisQuestions[currentQuestion].answer) {
    console.log("correct!");
    addPoints();
}

else {
    console.log("incorrect!");
    removePoints();
    appendTime();
}
currentQuestion++;

if (currentQuestion < chrisQuestions.length) {
    chrisQuiz();
}

else {
    console.log("the game has ended!");
    endQuiz();
}
}

// nataly quiz
function natalyQuiz() {
rules.innerHTML = '';

let question = natalyQuestions[currentQuestion];

rules.appendChild(questionDisplay);

for (i = 0; i < question.choices.length; i++) {
    questionDisplay.textContent = question.question;

    let answersBtn = document.createElement("button");
    answersBtn.className = "choices-class btn btn-lg btn-outline-dark m-2 col-4";
    answersBtn.textContent = question.choices[i];
    rules.append(answersBtn);
    answersBtn.addEventListener("click", natalyCheckAnswer);
};
}

function natalyCheckAnswer(event) {
let chosenAnswer = event.target.textContent;
console.log({ chosenAnswer });

if (chosenAnswer === natalyQuestions[currentQuestion].answer) {
    console.log("correct!");
    addPoints();
}

else {
    console.log("incorrect!");
    removePoints();
    appendTime();
}
currentQuestion++;

if (currentQuestion < natalyQuestions.length) {
    natalyQuiz();
}

else {
    console.log("the game has ended!");
    endQuiz();
}
}

// mikey quiz
mikeyQuiz = function () {
rules.innerHTML = '';

let question = mikeyQuestions[currentQuestion];

rules.appendChild(questionDisplay);

for (i = 0; i < question.choices.length; i++) {
    questionDisplay.textContent = question.question;

    let answersBtn = document.createElement("button");
    answersBtn.className = "choices-class btn btn-lg btn-outline-dark m-2 col-4";
    answersBtn.textContent = question.choices[i];
    rules.append(answersBtn);
    answersBtn.addEventListener("click", mikeyCheckAnswer);
};
}

function mikeyCheckAnswer(event) {
let chosenAnswer = event.target.textContent;
console.log({ chosenAnswer });

if (chosenAnswer === mikeyQuestions[currentQuestion].answer) {
    console.log("correct!");
    addPoints();
}

else {
    console.log("incorrect!");
    removePoints();
    appendTime();
}
currentQuestion++;

if (currentQuestion < mikeyQuestions.length) {
    mikeyQuiz();
}

else {
    console.log("the game has ended!");
    endQuiz();
}
}

// melissa quiz
function melissaQuiz() {
rules.innerHTML = '';

let question = melissaQuestions[currentQuestion];

rules.appendChild(questionDisplay);

for (i = 0; i < question.choices.length; i++) {
    questionDisplay.textContent = question.question;

    let answersBtn = document.createElement("button");
    answersBtn.className = "choices-class btn btn-lg btn-outline-dark m-2 col-4";
    answersBtn.textContent = question.choices[i];
    rules.append(answersBtn);
    answersBtn.addEventListener("click", melissaCheckAnswer);
};
}

function melissaCheckAnswer(event) {
let chosenAnswer = event.target.textContent;
console.log({ chosenAnswer });

if (chosenAnswer === melissaQuestions[currentQuestion].answer) {
    console.log("correct!");
    addPoints();
}

else {
    console.log("incorrect!");
    removePoints();
    appendTime();
}
currentQuestion++;

if (currentQuestion < melissaQuestions.length) {
    melissaQuiz();
}

else {
    console.log("the game has ended!");
    endQuiz();
}
}

// Marlyn quiz
marlynQuiz = function () {
rules.innerHTML = '';

let question = marlynQuestions[currentQuestion];

rules.appendChild(questionDisplay);

for (i = 0; i < question.choices.length; i++) {
    questionDisplay.textContent = question.question;

    let answersBtn = document.createElement("button");
    answersBtn.className = "choices-class btn btn-lg btn-outline-dark m-2 col-4";
    answersBtn.textContent = question.choices[i];
    rules.append(answersBtn);
    answersBtn.addEventListener("click", marlynCheckAnswer);
};
}

function marlynCheckAnswer(event) {
let chosenAnswer = event.target.textContent;
console.log({ chosenAnswer });

if (chosenAnswer === marlynQuestions[currentQuestion].answer) {
    console.log("correct!");
    addPoints();
}

else {
    console.log("incorrect!");
    removePoints();
    appendTime();
}
currentQuestion++;

if (currentQuestion < marlynQuestions.length) {
    marlynQuiz();
}

else {
    console.log("the game has ended!");
    endQuiz();
}
}


// time penalty
function appendTime() {
count -= 10;
if (count < 0) {
    count = 0;
}
}

// add to score if question answered correctly
function addPoints() {
score += 10;
}

function removePoints() {
score -= 5;
if (score < 0) {
    score = 0;
}
}

function endQuiz(timer) {
clearInterval(timer);

// timer
seconds.className = "display-none";
seconds.className = "display-none";
// questions
rules.className = 'display-none';
// score 
titleWarning.className = "display-none";

// final score showing

const totalScore = document.createElement("h2");
totalScore.className = "scary-text";
totalScore.textContent = `Your final score is : ${score} / 100`;

scoreDiv.append(totalScore, playAgainBtn);
}

playAgainBtn.addEventListener("click", function () {
location.reload();
})


startBtn.addEventListener("click", function () {
chooseQuiz();
});